John R. Brandon, PhD

jbrandon@gmail.com LinkedIn (206) 919–6541 GitHub San Francisco Bay Area Google Scholar

John provides modeling and statistical support as an independent consultant to his clients, including: a National Science Foundation (NSF) research center initiative, and The Makah Tribal Council. This work involves evaluating the performance of alternative management strategies using computational statistics. He also prepares testimony on these applications as an expert witness under federal judicial oversight of aboriginal whaling. Previously, he worked as a staff consultant, leading the development of survey designs based on statistical power analysis. These studies successfully informed operational management decisions for foreign and multinational corporate clients under multi-billion dollar natural resource development projects.

| | Professional Positions |
|--------------|---|
| 2016—present | Population Dynamics and Statistical Consultant to the Makah Tribal Council. |
| 2014-present | Management Strategy Consultant to the (U.S.) Science Center for Marine Fisheries. |
| 2009–2015 | Biostatistician / Survey Scientist (Staff at LGL and Greeneridge Sciences, Inc.). |
| | Academic Degrees |
| 2003-2009 | PhD, School of Aquatic and Fisheries Sciences, University of Washington (UW). |
| 1994-1998 | BSc, Ecology, Behavior and Evolution, University of California, San Diego (UCSD). |
| | Additional Coursework |

- High Performance Scientific Computing, Applied Mathematics 483/583, UW.
- Computer Intensive Statistical Techniques, SIO-279, Scripps Institute of Oceanography.
- UCSD Computer Science and Engineering Department Extension:
 - Visual Basic II: Intermediate, CSE-40159.
 - Visual Basic III: Advanced Programming with ActiveX/COM, CSE-40328.

Applied Statistics

- Simulation modeling of dynamic feedback systems (e.g. Brandon et. al. 2017 + open source code).
- Bayesian inference (e.g. Brandon et. al. 2007).
- Regression / Generalized linear models.
- Mixed-effects and Bayesian hierarchical models.

Computing Experience

- Git / GitHub.
- R %>% R Markdown Notebooks.
- Bash shell scripting and Makefiles.
- Fortran 90/95.
- AD Model Builder C++ language expression for auto differentiation.
- ∘ LAT⊨X
- Twitter @BeachPooBot